# **Emily A. Kelton**

### emily.kelton@comcast.net

#### SUMMARY:

Creative professional with knowledge in HTML, CSS, photography, lighting and design. Extensive experience in photo retouching, editing, and digital manipulation, as well as preparing images for print and digital publishing. Proven track record in meeting deadlines and working independently. Strong written and verbal communication skills.

#### CORE PROFICIENCIES INCLUDE:

• HTML5 • CSS3 • Digital Photography • Adobe Photoshop • Adobe Illustrator • Image editing • Creative Design • Problem Solving • Organization • Communication • Writing • Customer Service • Troubleshooting • Editing • Proofreading

#### PHOTOGRAPHY AWARDS:

The Peace Project: Inspiration Award, 2010

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

**Emily A. Kelton Photography**, Seattle, WA. Owner, photographer: April, 2005 – present

- Photograph a variety of clients, products and events.
- Edit images using Adobe Photoshop CS products and Adobe Lightroom.
- Maintain professional website: http://www.eakweb.com.
- · Conduct market research.
- · Maintain a large image archive.
- Design and write content for print, web and email.
- Manage sales and accounts.
- Provide technical support for ecommerce system.

Getty Images, Seattle, WA.

Support Technician: April 1998 – July 1999

- Provided technical support for the Getty Images online photo database and website, as well as their CD products.
- Provided solutions to customers purchasing, downloading, using and printing Getty products.
- Acted as liaison between the customer and Getty color management and image editing departments.
- Set up email support software and trained staff on use.
- Wrote Knowledge Base articles for internal use by the support staff.
- Added keywords and metatags to images to increase successful searching.

#### **EDUCATION:**

Associate of Applied Science - Graphic Design, Seattle Central Community College, Seattle, Washington Bachelor's of Arts - English, University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas

#### COMMUNITY:

Librarian for Gay City Library: December 2013 – present.

Served as Vice-Chair on the Shoreline Cooperative Preschool's Board of Directors: September 2008 – June 2009.